So in this notebook, I'll be leading you through a Word2Vec implementation in PyTorch.
在此 notebook 中 我将演示如何在 PyTorch 中实现 Word2Vec 模型
Now, you've just learned about the idea behind embeddings in general.
你刚刚学习了嵌入的基本原理
For any dataset with lots of classes or input dimensions like a large word vocabulary,
如果数据集包含大量类别或输入维数很高 例如大型词汇表
we're basically skipping the one-hot encoding step,
我们将跳过独热编码步骤
which would result in extremely long input vectors of mostly zeros.
因为独热编码会生成很长的输入向量 向量中的元素基本为 0
We're taking advantage of the fact that when
当独热向量与权重矩阵相乘时
one-hot vectors are multiplied by a weight matrix,
结果会返回一行值
we will just get one row of values back.
我们将利用这个规律
For example, if we have a one-hot vector that has its fourth index on,
例如 假设有一个独热向量 它的第四个索引的值为 1
and we multiply this by a weight matrix,
我们将此向量与权重矩阵相乘
we'll get the fourth row of weights back as a result.
结果将返回该矩阵的第四行
So, what we can do,
因此我们可以
is actually just have input numbers instead of one-hot vectors,
直接使用输入数字 而不是独热向量
and then we can use an embedding weight matrix to look up the correct output.
然后在嵌入权重矩阵中查询正确的输出
In this case, we see the word heart is encoded as the integer 958,
我们看到 heart 编码为整数 958
and we can look up the embedding vector for this word in
我们可以在嵌入权重矩阵的第 958 行
the 958 row of an embedding weight matrix,
查询该字词的嵌入向量
this is also often called a lookup table.
这个表通常称为查询表
In text analysis, this is great.
在文本分析过程中 这种流程很方便
Because we already know that we can convert a vocabulary of words into integer tokens.
因为我们已经知道如何将词汇表转换为整数标记
So, each unique word will have a corresponding integer value.
每个唯一字词都对应一个整数值
If we have a vocabulary of 10,000 words,
如果词汇表有 10,000 个字词
we'll have a 10,000 row embedded weight matrix,
则嵌入权重矩阵将有 10,000 行
where we can look up the correct output values.
我们可以从中查询正确的输出值
These output values which will just be rows in
这些输出值在此权重矩阵里用行表示
this weight matrix will be a vector representation of that input word.
它们是该输入字词的向量表示法
These representations are called embeddings,
这些表示法称为嵌入
and they have as many values as is weight matrix has columns.
它们的值数量与权重矩阵的列数相同
This width is called the embedding dimension,
这个宽度称为嵌入维度
it's usually some value in the hundreds.
通常以数百个计
Now, Word2Vec is a special algorithm that basically says,
Word2Vec 是一种特殊算法
"Any words that appear in the same context in
该算法指出“在给定文本中 出现在相同上下文里的任何字词”
a given text should have similar vector representations."
“应该具有相似的向量表示法”
So context in this case,
上下文是指
basically means the words that come before and after a word of interest.
出现在目标字词前后的字词
Here are a couple of examples.
举几个例子
In a body of text, you'll find a variety of sentences,
在这段文本里有几个句子
and these ones all involve drinking some beverage.
这些句子都是在描述喝饮料
In some of these cases, even if I removed a word of interests,
对于某些句子 即使我删除目标字词
you may be able to guess what goes in there,
你也能根据上下文信息
just based on the context words surrounding it.
猜出删除的字词是什么
So here it says, "I often drink coffee in the mornings.
这段文本为“I often drink coffee in the mornings”
When I'm thirsty, I drink water,
“When I'm thirsty, I drink water”
and I drink tea before I go to sleep."
“I drink tea, before I go to sleep”
The mention of I drink before these words,
这些字词前面的“I drink”
makes these contexts similar.
表明上下文相似
So, we'll expect these words coffee, water,
因此 coffee、water 和 tea
and tea to have similar word embeddings.
应该具有相似的词嵌入
You can imagine that if we look at a large enough text,
如果我们查看的是一大段文本
we may also see that coffee is more closely associated with morning time and so on.
你可能会发现 coffee 与 morning time 紧密相关 等等
So, just by looking at a word of interest and some context words that surround it,
通过查看目标字词和一些上下文信息
Word2Vec can find similarities between words and relationships between them.
Word2Vec 能够发现字词之间的相似性和关系
In fact, for such similar words,
对于相似的字词
Word2Vec should produce vectors that are very close in vector space,
Word2Vec 应该会生成在向量空间里很靠近的向量
different words will be some distance away from each other.
不同的字词相互之间距离较远
In this way, we're actually able to do vector arithmetic,
这样我们便能够进行向量运算
and that's how Word2Vec confined mappings between
Word2Vec 正是通过这种方式
words in the past and present tense for example.
发现过去时态和现在时态字词之间的映射关系
So, mapping the verb drink to drinking,
例如 将动词 drink 映射到 drinking
and swam to swimming,
与将 swam 映射到 swimming
is going to be the same transformation in vector space.
在向量空间里将是相同的转换
In practice, Word2Vec is implemented in one of two ways.
Word2Vec 的实现方式有两种
The first option is to basically give our model the context,
第一种方式会为模型提供上下文
so several words surrounding a word of interest,
即目标字词前后的几个字词
and have it tried to predict the missing word.
然后让模型预测缺失的目标字词
So, context words in and a single word out,
即输入上下文字词并输出一个字词
this is called the continuous bag of words or a CBOW model.
这称之为连续词袋模型 简称 CBOW 模型
The second option is the reverse,
第二种方式正好相反
to input our word of interests and have our model tried to predict the context.
输入目标字词 并让模型预测上下文字词
So, one word n and a few you context words out.
即输入一个字词并输出几个上下文字词
This is the skip-gram model,
这称之为 Skip-Gram 模型
and we'll be implementing Word2Vec in
我们将以这种方式实现 Word2Vec
this way because it's been shown to work a bit better.
因为经验表明这种方式效果更好
You'll notice that for either of these models,
请注意 对于这两种模型
we'll also have to formalize the idea of context to be a window of a specified size.
都必须记住 上下文是具有指定大小的窗口
So, something like two words before and two words after a word of interest.
例如目标字词前面的两个字词和后面的两个字词
Here, for an input word w at time t,
对于在时间 t 的输入字词 w
we have context words from t minus two to t plus two,
上下文字词是从 t-2 到 t+2 的字词
that is minus two words in the past and plus two in the future.
即过去的前两个字词和未来的后两个字词
Notice that the context does not include the original word of interest.
注意 上下文不包含原始目标字词
So, now that you've been introduced to this notebook and the Word2Vec skip-gram model.
介绍完此 notebook 和 Word2Vec Skip-Gram 模型后
Next, I'll show you the data that we'll be working with and give you your first exercise.
接下来我将演示我们要处理的数据并布置第一道练习